Michael Voecks

Address 2437 Ginny Way, **Mobile Phone** +1 (720) 979 7100

Lafayette, CO 80026 Email voecks.michael@gmail.com

Personal Profile

I am a graduate with a masters in computer science from the University of Colorado Boulder and have a passion for combining math and technology to help businesses solve problems. I combine a results driven work ethic from my experience in private industry with a long term project stability mindset I garnered through my time as a researcher for the government.

Education

2015-2019 Bachelors of Science in Computer Science - The University of Colorado, Boulder

- Minor in Applied Mathematics (Probability and Statistics)
- Boettcher Scholar Award Recipient
- Engineering Honors Program
- Cumulative GPA: 3.825

2019-2020 Masters of Science in Computer Science - The University of Colorado, Boulder

- Emphasis in Data Science
- Cumulative GPA: 3.750

Employment History

Aug 2020 - Freelance Development, 2437 Ginny Way, Lafayette, CO 80026 Present Web and SQL Systems Developer

- Sashco
 - Led a project with the manufacturing company Sashco to switch EDI providers and allow for easier order placement and vendor response with zero downtime
- Mountain Sports Club
 - Customized the WordPress SQL database for mountainsportsclub.com to allow for a large variety of customers, products, and discounts
 - Used HTML, CSS, and PHP to integrate the WordPress database with many areas of the website to create long term solution with low maintenance for the site owner

Technologies: HTML, CSS, PHP, SQL, WordPress, Dynamics GP, EDI

May 2019 - Sashco: Home Solutions, 10300 E 107th Pl, Brighton, CO 80601 Sep 2019 SQL Systems Developer

- Captured user requirements, designed solution, and implemented SQL scripts to automate the generation and archival of all orders and invoices to optimize business results
- Created real-time status reports to provide daily insights for executive management and assisted with data interpretation for company decisions
- Facilitated communications between departments to standardize workflow through shared technologies and applications

Technologies: SQL, SSRS, Dynamics GP, Visual Studio, Power BI

Jun 2017 - National Institute of Standards and Technology, 325 Broadway, Boulder, CO 80305 May 2018 Data Scientist

- Created and maintained an SQL database for storing TM-500 test data and wrote scripts to facilitate their retrieval and analysis used by researchers to study radio interference
- Defined the methodology for analyzing the robustness of pulse width estimators and created a new measure for pulse duration based on median absolute deviation to be used on signals in high noise environments
- Primary author of research paper on robust pulse width estimation, submitted for review to the internal NIST review board, currently pending publication

Technologies: Python, Numpy, Scipy, SQL, Matlab, Mathematica

Jun 2014 - National Institute of Standards and Technology, 325 Broadway, Boulder, CO 80305 Aug 2015 *Materials Scientist*

- Co-led a project to create water filtration solutions through iron-nickel nanoparticles intended to find a cost effective solution to clean water in developing countries
- Presented and defended my research at the 2015 American Chemical Society Conference in Denver
- Co-Author of team research paper on the removal of azo dye using bimetallic ironnickel nanoparticles; *Journal of Nanomaterials* "Removal of Synthetic Azo Dye Using Bimetallic Nickel-Iron Nanoparticles," Volume 2019, Article ID 9807605,

https://doi.org/10.1155/2019/9807605

May 2013- CRMCulture, 1455 Dixon Avenue, Suite 300, Lafayette, CO 80026 Aug 2013 SQL Developer

- · Tested and debugged platform software changes prior to implementation
- Developed automated SQL scripts to remove orphaned entries in the database
- Gained experience in SQL and C# through independent research and self-instruction

Technologies: SQL, C#, Microsoft SQL Server

Community Experience and Interests

New Venture Challenge Honorable Mention: 2019

Worked with a team of three people to create, market, and develop a distributed computing business with the goal of providing distributed computing solutions to academics and researchers. Recieved an honorable mention for our business pitch at the CU Boulder New Venture Challenge.

■ Semester at Sea: Jan 2017 - May 2017

Visited 13 countries in Asia and Africa while taking courses on a ship with 400 students from around the world. After which I traveled throughout Europe and took a Maymester class in Rome through CU Boulder.

■ Lighting Designer: May 2018 - Present

Worked closely with a local cover band to design, develop, and test a portable stage lighting setup with the goal of performing shows at local venues.

■ Eagle Scout

Created a historical walk in Lafayette, CO with a brochure that takes people on a self-guided tour of the Coal Creek Trail.